<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Session Recap on Blog</title><link>https://blog.sions.org/tags/session-recap/</link><description>Recent content in Session Recap on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sions.org/tags/session-recap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sarpine, Second Session</title><link>https://blog.sions.org/posts/sarpine-second/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sions.org/posts/sarpine-second/</guid><description>We finished up a game session, and I thought I would give a bit of a summary. This is more for recurring writing exercises than anything else.
We start the session with our intrepid heroes completing their daily tasks. They haven&amp;rsquo;t formed an adventuring party yet, and they haven&amp;rsquo;t exchanged names at this point in the story.
With the last of the continent&amp;rsquo;s unified army having arrived, most members of this encampment the size of a small city are informed training will start today.</description><content>&lt;p>We finished up a game session, and I thought I would give a bit of a summary. This is more for recurring writing exercises than anything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We start the session with our intrepid heroes completing their daily tasks. They haven&amp;rsquo;t formed an adventuring party yet, and they haven&amp;rsquo;t exchanged names at this point in the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the last of the continent&amp;rsquo;s unified army having arrived, most members of this encampment the size of a small city are informed training will start today. Upon completing their assignments, Xen and Storm proceed to their designated training location. Which appears to largely be seating arranged around a stage, large enough for a few hundred at a time. After most of the people in attendance take their seats, the leader of training, Captain Sandaman, informs all in attendance that over the next several days they will have a chance to act in a role as a leader and gain plenty of experience acting through situations that have been recovered through the memories of soldiers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Captain Sandaman again directs all to sit before several mages on the stage proceed to cast a unique spell that places all present under a deep trance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shortly after everything went dark, Xen and Storm found themselves walking along a corridor in a cave. Tasked with securing the contents of the cave until assistance could show up, they delved deeper. The small group exchanged names and consists of Xen, Storm, Alan, and Kernick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The party eventually finds an orange substance on the wall that appears to be Dragonspark, a physical manifestation of the ley lines. Xen, learning of its ability to combust, starts to give it a wider berth due to the motes of flame around his head for light. The party proceeds to take a brief break before starting on the goal of securing the cave. A brief exploration led to a couple of revelations. The first being that there was a spark spring—a physical spring caused as a result of the leyline. The second is that there appears to be a pile of corpses, skeletons, and weapons. Some amphibious merfolk creatures seem to be using this as part of their hunting grounds. The tridents and a body of underground water appear to correlate with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before long, the merfolk came ashore and attacked, as did a being that seemed to be blurry, coming out of the wall near the spark spring. Quickly dispatching them with an explosive set-off near the spark spring, the party started to lick their wounds as everything faded back to what they knew as reality.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>