<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>unraid on Blog</title><link>https://blog.sions.org/tags/unraid/</link><description>Recent content in unraid on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sions.org/tags/unraid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Image Change</title><link>https://blog.sions.org/posts/image-change/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sions.org/posts/image-change/</guid><description>While changing what source image a docker container in unRaid was using, the Docker managment service encountered an error. The error itself I forgot to write down. But what is normally a typical process of &amp;ldquo;download new image, stop old container. create new container, cleanup old image.&amp;rdquo; was interrupted and it left the container in a down state. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t good primarily because I am lazy and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend the mental power and try to come up with what the previous config options were so there can be no change except what image is being used.</description><content>&lt;p>While changing what source image a docker container in unRaid was using, the Docker managment service encountered an error. The error itself I forgot to write down. But what is normally a typical process of &amp;ldquo;download new image, stop old container. create new container, cleanup old image.&amp;rdquo; was interrupted and it left the container in a down state. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t good primarily because I am lazy and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend the mental power and try to come up with what the previous config options were so there can be no change except what image is being used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After fixing the underlying cause for what caused the error. (The ghcr package for this particular repo was marked as private only). I started trying to recover what was a downed service. A brief spat of web searches and I discover that when creating a custom docker image 2 things are true. The first that it&amp;rsquo;s stored as an xml template in &lt;code>/boot/config/plugins/dockerMan/templates-user&lt;/code>. The second that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to open the XML file and try to transcode as I had thought. You can simply go to &lt;code>Docker&lt;/code> -&amp;gt; &lt;code>Add Container&lt;/code> -&amp;gt; &lt;code>Templates&lt;/code> and all of your custom docker invocations are contained there as templates. Easy Peasy.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>